Register to The E.Y. Harburg Collection
Yale University Music Library
- Writings, 1929-1968; Series I; 20 boxes
  - Writings: Lyrics, Libretti, and Scores
    - Selection of published piano-vocal scores with lyrics in leather bound volume, 1930-1941
      - The Wizard of Oz (1939; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - A Day At the Circus (1939; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs) (Box 3, Folder 17)
          "Lydia, the Tattooed Lady" -- 9 pages
        - Hold On To Your Hats (1940; E.Y. Harburg-Burton Lane songs) (Box 3, Folder 17)
          "There's a Great Day Coming Mañana" -- 5 pages
          "Don't Let It Get You Down" -- 4 pages
          "Would You Be So Kindly" -- 4 pages
          "The World Is in My Arms" -- 3 pages
      - Hooray for What! (1937; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
        - "God's Country", 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Down with Love", 5 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Moanin' in the Mornin'", 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "I've Gone Romantic on You", 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Life's a Dance" (or "On With the Dance"), 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - The Singing Kid (1936; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "I Love to Sing-a", 6 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "You're the Cure for What Ails Me", 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Save Me Sister", 6 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Gold Diggers (1937; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
        - "Speaking of the Weather", 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Let's Put Our Heads Together", 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Stage Struck (1936; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
        - "In Your Own Quiet Way", 5 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Fancy Meeting You", 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Leave It To Lester, (1930) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "I'm Yours" (E.Y. Harburg-Johnny Green), 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Americana, (1932) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Brother, Can You Spare a Dime?" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Walk a Little Faster, (1932) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "April in Paris" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Take a Chance, (1933) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "It's Only a Paper Moon" (E.Y. Harburg-Rose-Arlen), 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Independent song, (1941) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - "Honorable Moon" (E.Y. Harburg-Schwartz-Ira Gershwin), 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Hold On To Your Hats (N.Y. opening: Sam S. Shubert Theatre, 1940 Nov 11) (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Two typescripts of book in 2 acts [by Guy Bolton, Matt Brooks & Eddie Davis], 109 pages, 113 pages (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Hold On To Your Hats
      - Typed lyrics with holograph corrections & annotations (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Way Out West Where the East Begins", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Hold On To Your Hats", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Walkin' Along Minding My Business", 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "The World is in My Arms", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Would You Be So Kindly", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Life Was Pie for the Pioneer", 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "There's a Great Day Comin' Mañana", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Then You Were Never in Love", 2 different versions, 2 pages, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Down On the Dude Ranch", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "She Came, She Saw, She Can-Canned", 2 different copies, 1 page each (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Old Timer", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Looks Like I'm Off o' Ya (Now That I'm On to Ya)" [not used in N.Y.], 1 page (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - "Bedtime on the Prairie" [not used in N.Y.], 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Story outline for possible television treatment, (1957); typed, 2 copies, 9 pages each (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Seven Sweethearts (MGM, 1942)
      - Prologue [by E.Y. Harburg] to screenplay (Box 3, Folder 20)
        Typed lyrics with holograph annotation & corrections -- 1 page
        News clipping: Knickerbocker Weekly, 1942 Sep 14, including lyrics -- 1 page
    - Song of Russia (MGM, 1943)
      - "And Russia Is Her Name" (E.Y. Harburg-Kern), 2 different copies, 1 page each (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Cabin in the Sky (MGM, 1943; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
      - "Happiness is Just a Thing Called Joe" (Box 3, Folder 20)
        Studio piano-vocal score with holograph annotation -- 3 pages
      - "Li'l Black Sheep", 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - "Ain't It de Truth", 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - "Life's Full of Consequences" (or "Dat Old Debbil Consequence"), 2 different versions, 2 pages each (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - "Jezebel Jones", 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - "Some Folk Work", 1 page (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Thousands Cheer (MGM, 1943)
      - "Let There Be Music" (E.Y. Harburg-Earl Brent), 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 20)
        Published piano-vocal score with lyrics, refrain only
    - Can't Help Singing (Universal Pictures, 1944)
      - Typed lyrics with holograph corrections (Box 3, Folder 21)
        "Can't Help Singing" -- 1 page
        "More and More" -- 1 page
        "Californ-I-Ay" -- 2 pages
        "Elbow Room" -- 1 page
        "There'll Come a Day" [with holograph annotation] -- 1 page
      - Holograph draft notes and lyrics, in pencil (Box 3, Folder 21)
        "More and More" -- 4 pages
        "Californ-I-Ay" -- 16 pages
        "There'll Come a Day" -- 16 pages
      - Red leather-bound volume of 4 published piano-vocal Scores with lyrics, holographed by Jerome Kern (Box 3, Folder 22)
        "Any Moment Now" -- 3 pages
        "Californ-I-Ay" -- 5 pages
        "Can't Help Singing" -- 3 pages
    - Bloomer Girl (N.Y. opening: Sam S. Shubert Theatre, 1944 Oct 5; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
      - Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, carbon copies (Box 4, Folder 23)
        "When the Boys Come Home" (original) -- 2 pages
        "Evalina" -- 1 page
        "The Farmer's Daughter" – 2 pages
        "Pretty as a Picture" – 1 page
        "It Was Good Enough For Grandma" -- 2 pages
        "The Eagle & Me" -- 2 pages
        "Right As the Rain" -- 1 page
        "The Rakish Young Man With the Whiskers" -- 1 page
        "Sunday in Cicero Falls" -- 4 pages
        "Liza Crossing the Ice" -- 1 page
        "I Never Was Born" -- 2 versions, 1 carbon & 1 typed, 1 page each
      - Holograph draft notes and lyrics, in pencil (Box 4, Folder 23)
        "When the Boys Come Home" -- 1 page
        "Evalina" -- 2 pages
        "Welcome Hinges" -- 1 page
        "Farmer's Daughter" -- 3 pages
        "Right As the Rain" -- 2 pages
        "T'morra' T'morra'" -- 7 pages
        "Lullaby" -- 4 pages
      - Holograph draft notes for lyrics & script, in pencil, 16 pages (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Typed script by Sig Herzig & Fred Saidy with lyrics by E.Y. Harburg, 85 pages (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Typed screenplay, adaptation by John Patrick for 20th Century Fox [unproduced; no date] [pages 1-5 missing], 44 pages (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Blue Holiday [All-Black revue] (N.Y. opening: Belasco Theatre, 1945 May 21)
      - "Free and Equal Blues" (Earl Robinson-E.Y. Harburg) (Box 4, Folder 26)
        [Song was first presented 1944 Nov 6 on CBS Network TV by Democratic National Committee.]
        Piano-vocal score with lyrics, photocopy -- 6 pages
        Typed script passages with lyrics, photocopy -- 3 pages
        Holograph notes for song, in pencil -- 9 pages
    - Unity Fair (Presented by Norman Corwin for CBS radio broadcast 1945 Jun 17)
      [Based on program of United Nations opening in San Francisco, 1945 Apr]
      - ["Meetin'"] (E.Y. Harburg-Robinson), 6 pages (Box 4, Folder 27)
        [E.Y. Harburg describes this song as being in the show, but it does not appear in the script]
        Piano-vocal score with lyrics, holograph annotations -- 6 pages
      - "The Same Boat, Brother" (E.Y. Harburg-Robinson) (Box 4, Folder 27)
        Piano-vocal score with lyrics, holograph annotation -- 9 pages
        Holograph lyrics, draft in pencil -- 9 pages
      - Typed script, complete, with lyrics -- 26 pages (E.Y. Harburg-Robinson) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - California (Paramount Pictures, 1946)
      - Bound volume of mimeographed studio piano-vocal score with lyrics (Box 4, Folder 28)
        "California" -- 2 pages
        "California or Bust" -- 3 pages
        "I Should'a Stood in Pennsylvania" -- 5 pages
        "Gold Discover Montage" -- 23 pages
        "Said I to My Heart, Said I" -- 4 pages
        "Lily-I-Lay-De-O" -- 10 pages
      - "Said I to My Heart, Said I" (Box 4, Folder 29)
        Holograph lyrics, draft in pencil -- 3 pages
    - Centennial Summer (20th Century Fox, 1946)
      - "Cinderella Sue" (E.Y. Harburg-Kern), 4 pages (Box 4, Folder 30)
        Published piano-vocal score with lyrics
        [See also: Box 5, Folder 31. Verso of first draft of Finian's Rainbow is complete script by Michael Kanin for Centennial Summer - 151 pages]
    - Finian's Rainbow (N.Y. opening: 46th Street Theatre, 1947 Jan 10; book by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, music & lyrics by Burton Lane & E.Y. Harburg)
      - Holograph draft of stage play with lyrics, in pencil, 132 pages (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Packet of typed correspondence, between Rufus Atwood (president, Kentucky State College) and various librarians & academics, regarding "some classic piece of literature... in which the characters are Negroes." (E.Y. Harburg annotation: "Research on Finian's."), 1948 Nov-Dec; 14 pages (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Synopsis of story by E.Y. Harburg, typed, 10 pages (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Typed draft of stage play by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, 89 pages (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Typed lyrics (Box 5, Folder 33)
        "This Time of Year" -- 1 page
        "How Are Things in Glocca Morra?" -- 1 page
        "If This Isn't Love" -- 2 pages
        "Something Sort of Grandish" -- 1 page
        "Necessity" -- 1 page
        "That Great Come-and-Get-It-Day" -- 2 pages
        "When the Idle Poor Become the Idle Rich" -- 2 pages
        "Old Devil Moon" -- 1 page
        "The Begat" -- 2 pages
        "When I'm Not Near the Girl I Love" -- 1 page
      - Book: Lenox Robinson, Killycreggs in Twilight and Other Plays (London: MacMillan & Co., Ltd., 1939) [Holograph inscription: "used in research for Finian"], 290 pages (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Book: E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, Finian's Rainbow, a Musical Satire (New York: Random House, 1947), 143 pages (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Red leather-bound volume of published piano-vocal scores with lyrics (Box 5, Folder 36)
        "How Are Things in Glocca Morra?" -- 4 pages
        "Look to the Rainbow" -- 3 pages
        "Old Devil Moon" -- 4 pages
        "Something Sort of Grandish" -- 3 pages
        "If This Isn't Love" -- 4 pages
        "Necessity" -- 5 pages
        "That Great Come-and-Get-It-Day" -- 3 pages
        "When the Idle Poor Become the Idle Rich" -- 10 pages
        "The Begat" -- 8 pages
        "When I'm Not Near the Girl I Love" -- 6 pages
      - Published piano-vocal score with lyrics and complete piano score [including overture, finale, & incidental music], 134 pages (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Revised edition of published score, 137 pages (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Early film versions (unproduced) (Box 6, Folder 39)
        Placid Productions, Inc., animated film, final revised typed script -- 76 pages
        Placid Productions, Inc., animated film, script notes, holograph draft, in ink [on 1959 calendar sheets] -- 28 pages
        M.P.O. Productions film Typed script [holograph annotation: "Revised edition for M. P. O. Productions, 1960 "Deal with M.P.O. fell thru"] -- 81 pages
      - Early film versions (unproduced) (Box 6, Folder 41)
        - [John Hubley's animation, 1961?] (Box 6, Folder 41)
          Typed draft screenplay -- 52 pages
          Continuity outline by Fred Saidy, typed -- 4 pages
      - Warner Bros. film, released 1968 (Screenplay by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, music & lyrics by Burton Lane & E.Y. Harburg) (Box 6, Folder 42)
        Holograph first draft screenplay in ink & pencil with several additional pages [by Fred Saidy?] 1966 Dec-1967 Jan -- 104 pages
      - Warner Bros. screenplay, typed draft with corrections [Act II, Sc. 1, p. 9 missing], 106 pages (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Warner Bros. screenplay, typed final draft & copy, 83 pages each (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Warner Bros. screenplay, bound photocopy of typed draft [E.Y. Harburg annotation: "Before adulteration by Joe Landon & Francis F. Coppola"], 1967 Jan 11; 170 pages (Box 7, Folder 45)
      - [Revised] final typed draft screenplay by E.Y. Harburg & Saidy, 1967 Jan 27, photocopy, 129 pages (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - Studio "Estimating" script, 1967 Mar 10; 131 pages (Box 8, Folder 47)
      - Final typed draft screenplay by Francis Ford Coppola and Joseph Landon, 1967 Jun 21; 140 pages (Box 8, Folder 48)
        [See also: Correspondence, Box 21, Folder 169]
      - Bound final typed draft screenplay by E.Y. Harburg & Saidy, 1967 Jul 12; 148 pages (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Flahooley
      - N.Y. opening: Broadhurst Theatre, 1951 May 14; book by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, music & lyrics by Sammy Fain & E.Y. Harburg (Box 9, Folder 50)
        - "You Too Can Be a Puppet" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 copies -- 2 pages each
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 18 pages
        - "Who Says There Ain't No Santa Claus?" (Box 9, Folder 50)
        - "B.G. Bigelow Inc." (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 copies -- 3 pages each
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 26 pages
        - "Flahooley" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 19 pages
        - "He's Only Wonderful" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics, longer version -- 2 pages
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 4 pages
        - "The World Is Your Balloon" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          "Toy Balloon" early draft, typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 copies -- 1 page each
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 3 versions -- 2 pages each
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 24 pages
        - "Here's to Your Illusions" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 versions -- 3 pages each
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 12 pages
        - "Jump, Little Chillun" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 slightly different versions -- 3 copies each
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in pencil -- 3 pages
        - "Spirit of Capsulanti" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 3 slightly different versions -- 2 pages each
          Holograph draft lyrics, in ink -- 2 pages
        - "Happy Hunting" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 slightly different versions -- 2 pages each
          Holograph draft lyrics, in pencil -- 5 pages
        - "Come Back, Little Genie" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 versions (1 page, 2 pages)
        - "The Springtime Cometh" (Box 9, Folder 50)
          Typed lyrics with additional verses -- 5 pages
          Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in pencil -- 5 pages
        - "Christmas Song" [or "Christmas Carol" or "Season's Greetings"] (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - Typed script by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, lyrics not included, photocopy, 67 pages (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - [Jollyana--California production, 1952], 97 pages (Box 9, Folder 52)
        Typed script by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, revised, carbon copy
        Includes lyrics:
        "B.G. Bigelow Inc."
        "Cinderella"
        "The World Is Your Balloon"
        "Jollyanna"
        "Bigelow" (recitative)
        "You Too Can Be a Puppet"
        "A Little Bit of Magic"
        "Jump, Chillun, Jump"
        "What's Gonna Happen?"
        "Come Back, Little Genie"
        "Scheherazade Interlude"
        "How Lucky Can You Get?"
        "The Springtime Cometh"
      - [Jollyanna], 96 pages (Box 9, Folder 53)
        Revised typed script by E.Y. Harburg & Saidy, photocopy
        "Cinderella" (E.Y. Harburg-Fain)
        "Jollyanna" (E.Y. Harburg-William Friml)
        "Bigelow's Entrance" (E.Y. Harburg-William Friml)
        "A Little Bit of Magic" (E.Y. Harburg-Burton Lane)
        "What's Gonna Happen?" (E.Y. Harburg-Burton Lane)
        "Scheherazade Interlude" (E.Y. Harburg-Rimsky-Korsakoff)
      - ["The Little Doll Laughed"--intermediate version of Jollyanna], 55 pages (Box 9, Folder 54)
        Typed script without lyrics, carbon
      - [Jollyanna], 120 pages (Box 9, Folder 55)
        Typed rehearsal script with revisions, prop list, stage cues
    - Jamaica
      N.Y. opening: Imperial Theatre, 1957 Oct 31; Book by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, music & lyrics by Harold Arlen & E.Y. Harburg
      - Typed script, carbon, with holograph insert: "first version of Jamaica", 86 pages (Box 10, Folder 56)
      - Typed script for Philadelphia production, including 9 pages of revisions, 99 pages (Box 10, Folder 57)
      - Typed notes [from Harburg & Saidy] to director of Philadelphia production, carbon copy, 13 pages (Box 10, Folder 57)
      - Holograph notes for revisions, in ink & pencil, 3 pages (Box 10, Folder 57)
      - Revised typed script, carbon copy, 89 pages (Box 10, Folder 58)
      - Typed script, alternate version, Act I only, 49 pages (Box 10, Folder 59)
      - "Savannah" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics, 2 carbon copies -- 1 page each
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in ink -- 2 pages
      - "Savannah's Wedding Day", 2 pages (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in pencil & ink
      - "Pretty to Walk With (How a Man Gets Got)" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, carbon copy -- 2 pages
        Typed lyrics with holograph marks for vocal parts, carbon copy -- 2 pages
        Holograph working draft lyrics & notes in ink & pencil -- 9 pages
      - "Push de Button" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, carbon copy -- 3 pages
        Holograph working draft lyrics & notes, in ink & pencil -- 31 pages
      - "Incompatibility" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics with holograph additions, carbon copy -- 2 pages
        Holograph working draft lyrics & notes, in pencil -- 19 pages
      - "Little Biscuit" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Holograph working draft lyrics & notes, in pencil -- 18 pages
      - "Coconut Sweet" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, carbon copy -- 1 page
        Holograph lyrics, in ink -- 1 page
        Typed lyrics with holograph marks for vocal parts, carbon copy -- 1 page
        Holograph working draft lyrics & notes, in pencil & ink -- 23 pages
      - "Pity the Sunset" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Holograph working draft lyrics & notes, in pencil -- 7 pages
      - "Yankee Dollar", 2 pages (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in pencil
      - "What Good Does It Do?" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics, carbon copy -- 2 pages
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in ink -- 1 page
      - "Monkey in the Mango Tree" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in pencil -- 30 pages
      - "Take It Slow, Joe" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics, crossed out, carbon copy -- 1 page
        Typed patter, carbon copy -- 1 page
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 11 pages
      - "Leave de Atom Alone" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics, carbon copy -- 3 pages
        Typed rough draft lyrics, carbon copy -- 3 pages
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in pencil -- 17 pages
      - "For Every Fish" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed draft lyrics, carbon copy -- 2 pages
        Holograph working draft lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 8 pages
      - "I Don't Think I'll End It All Today" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections & refrain, in ink -- 3 pages
        Holograph working draft lyrics in ink & pencil -- 11 pages
      - "Napoleon" (Box 10, Folder 60)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, carbon copy, 2 drafts -- 2 pages each
        Holograph working draft lyrics & notes, in ink & pencil -- 8 pages
        Typed lists of historical names used for commercial products, etc. -- 4 pages
      - Miscellaneous unidentified holograph notes in ink & pencil, 29 pages (Box 10, Folder 60)
      - Leather-bound volume of published piano-vocal scores with lyrics (Box 11, Folder 62)
        "Savannah" -- 2 pages
        "Push de Button" -- 4 pages
        "Pretty to Walk With (How a Man Gets Got)" -- 4 pages
        "Little Biscuit" -- 3 pages
        "Coconut Sweet" -- 3 pages
        "What Good Does It Do?" -- 4 pages
        "Take It Slow, Joe" -- 2 pages
        "Ain't It de Truth?" -- 3 pages
        "I Don't Think I'll End It All Today" -- 6 pages
        "Napoleon" -- 3 pages
      - Jamaica 1963 production, Karamu Theatre, Cleveland, Ohio, 77 pages (Box 11, Folder 63)
        Typed script with revisions, mimeograph
    - The Happiest Girl in the World (N.Y. opening: Martin Beck Theatre, 1961 Apr 3; book by Fred Saidy & Henry Myers; lyrics by E.Y. Harburg to music by Offenbach.)
      - "Orpheus" [Early unproduced version], 56 pages (Box 11, Folder 64)
        Typed script of one-act play by Dalton Trumbo, 1957 Mar 18
        Includes lyrics by E.Y. Harburg:
        "The Greek Marine Hymn"
        "Eureka"
        "The Glory That Is Greece"
        "Never Trust a Poet"
        "Five Minutes of Spring"
        "Shall We Say Farewell"
        "A Simple Serenade"
        "The Happiest Girl in the World"
        "Never Be-Devil the Devil"
        "Barcarolle" [Adrift on a Star]
        "Shall We Say Farewell to Springtime"
      - "Lysistrata" [Early unproduced version, 1958] (Box 11, Folder 65)
        - Handwritten draft of outline dictated by E.Y. Harburg, in pencil (lyrics not included), 10 pages (Box 11, Folder 65)
        - Typed outline of story without lyrics, 14 pages (Box 11, Folder 65)
        - Carbon copy of above, 14 pages (Box 11, Folder 65)
      - "Lysistrata" [Early version], 26 pages (Box 11, Folder 66)
        Typed "expanded treatment" of story with lyrics, Act I only
      - "Lysistrata" [Early version], 38 pages (Box 11, Folder 66)
        Typed treatment, Acts I & II, Scene 2 missing, carbon copy, with lyrics:
        "Greek Marine Hymn"
        "Barcarolle"
        "Sabre Song" [not used]
        "Excuse My Laughter"
        "Lament" [Rhodope's Tavern]
        "Honestly"
      - "Lysistrata" [Early version]
        - Typed scene outline, carbon copy, 3 pages (Box 11, Folder 67)
        - Typed script by Fred Saidy & Henry Myers (no lyrics included), 1958 Dec 3; 67 pages (Box 11, Folder 67)
        - Typed script with handwritten revisions, 61 pages (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - Lyrics & Scores: "Lysistrata" [Early version]
        - "Cheers for the Hero" (Box 12, Folder 68)
          Typed lyrics -- 1 page
          ("Here Comes the Hero") Handwritten Lyrics, in ink -- 2 pages
          Holograph notes & rough draft lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 4 pages
        - "The Glory That Is Greece" (Box 12, Folder 68)
          Typed lyrics, 3 versions -- 3 pages each
          Holograph lyrics & notes, in ink & pencil -- 26 pages
          Piano-vocal score with lyrics, adaptation by Jay Gorney of tune from Offenbach's La Belle Hélène, handwritten in pencil -- 9 pages
          Photostatic copy of above -- 9 pages
        - "The Happiest Girl in the World" (Box 12, Folder 69)